{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"nerves","incorrectAnswers":["embryos","the study and psychology of organisms with regard to their functions and structures","mollusks"],"question":"What is Neurology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Bangladesh","incorrectAnswers":["Sri Lanka","Bhutan","Pakistan"],"question":"Which new country was formed in 1971 at the end of a conflict between Pakistan and India?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The Structure of Cells","incorrectAnswers":["Blood","Code-Breaking","Cloud Formations"],"question":"What is Cytology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cyprus","incorrectAnswers":["Slovakia","Nepal","United Kingdom"],"question":"Nicosia is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Conakry","incorrectAnswers":["Vaduz","Amman","Niamey"],"question":"What is the capital city of Guinea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Ludwig Wittgenstein","incorrectAnswers":["William of Ockham","Bertrand Russell","Immanuel Kant"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Whereof one cannot speak, thereof one must be silent'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"A man deeply immersed in the Edinburgh drug scene tries to clean up and get out.","incorrectAnswers":["A veteran sets out to reform his neighbor who tried to steal his prized possession.","A Polish Jew struggles to survive the destruction of the Warsaw ghetto of World War II.","King Arthur and his Knights embark on a search for a religious relic."],"question":"What is the plot of the movie Trainspotting?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Pizza","incorrectAnswers":["Dim Sum","Cou Cou and Flying Fish","Kabuli Pulao"],"question":"Which of these dishes would you most expect to find in Italy?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Caine","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Cruise","Michael Clarke Duncan","Jude Law"],"question":"Who won the 1999 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Dr. Wilbur Larch in The Cider House Rules?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Red","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Orange","Black"],"question":"Which of these colors would you find on the flag of Austria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"German","incorrectAnswers":["Turkish","Russian","Italian"],"question":"Prior to 1941, which language was traditionally written in a Gothic style called 'Fraktur'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Specials","incorrectAnswers":["Sex Pistols","UB40","The Selecter"],"question":"Which band had a hit in 1981 with the song 'Ghost Town'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Italian Renaissance","incorrectAnswers":["Art Nouveau","Surrealism","Romanticism"],"question":"The painting \"Primavera\" by Sandro Botticelli is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"James Watt","incorrectAnswers":["Joe Tyler","Nikolaus August Otto","Thomas Edison"],"question":"Which influential scientist improved the Newcomen steam engine, creating an efficient steam engine?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The war of American independence","incorrectAnswers":["The Napoleonic wars","World War 2","The English Civil War"],"question":"What war followed the original 'shot heard round the world'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Stephen King","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Allan Poe","Jack Vance"],"question":"Which author wrote ''Salem's Lot'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1942","incorrectAnswers":["1918","1926","1934"],"question":"When the penicillin first successfully used to treat a patient for septicaemia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"The Tin Drum","incorrectAnswers":["Gone With the Wind","In Our Time","Portnoy's Complaint"],"question":"Which book contains the character 'Oskar Matzerath'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the studio album 'The Joshua Tree'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"'You Are Not Alone' is a song by which musician?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Vivien Leigh","incorrectAnswers":["Holly Hunter","Whoopi Goldberg","Bette Davis"],"question":"Which actress played the role of Scarlett O'Hara in Gone with the Wind?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The relationships between living organisms and their environment","incorrectAnswers":["The death of stars","Windmills, watermills and animal engines","The practice of escaping from restraints"],"question":"What is Ecology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Matsumoto","incorrectAnswers":["Ōsaka","Kyoto","Yokohama"],"question":"Which city used to be called Satoyamabe?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Yukon","incorrectAnswers":["Alberta","British Columbia","Ontario"],"question":"Which territory is home to Mount Logan, Canada's highest peak?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Toddy","incorrectAnswers":["Mocha","Latte","Old Smoke"],"question":"What is the name of a spicy, hot beverage often served to cure a cold or sore throat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Vienna","incorrectAnswers":["Budapest","Berlin","Prague"],"question":"With which European city is Ultravox linked,songwise?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bethlehem","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Jericho","Nazareth"],"question":"Which city is believed to be the birthplace of Jesus of Nazareth?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Coca Cola","incorrectAnswers":["Dr Pepper","Lucozade","Irn Bru"],"question":"Which Significant Did Dr John Pemberton Of Atlanta Georgia Invent In 1886?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1941","incorrectAnswers":["1917","1925","1933"],"question":"In which year was Citizen Kane released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Eagles","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American country rock band released the song 'Hotel California'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Angelina Jolie","incorrectAnswers":["Marisa Tomei","Tilda Swinton","Brie Larson"],"question":"The role of Thena in the Marvel Cinematic Universe is played by which actor?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Albert Einstein","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen Hawking","Enrico Fermi","Paul Dirac"],"question":"Who proposed The Theory of Relativity?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greece","incorrectAnswers":["Luxembourg","Georgia","Serbia"],"question":"Athens is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The macadamia nut","incorrectAnswers":["The cashew nut","The pecan nut","The hazelnut"],"question":"Which nut is named after a Scottish-born chemist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Rooster","incorrectAnswers":["A Buck","A Dog","A Ram"],"question":"A male chicken is known as what?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Santiago","incorrectAnswers":["Valparaíso","Bogota","Cusco"],"question":"What is the capital of Chile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stringed","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Brass","Percussion"],"question":"What type of instrument is a sitar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Weather Report","incorrectAnswers":["The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which Band Was Formed In The 1970's By Fomer Miles Davis Band Members Joe Zawinul & Wayne Shorter?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Kakorrhaphiophobia","incorrectAnswers":["Ratoon","Octothorpe","Macrosmatic"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'fear of failure'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Sow","incorrectAnswers":["A Tigeress","A Gander","A Vixen"],"question":"What would you call a female boar?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Surrealism","incorrectAnswers":["Dutch and Flemish Renaissance","Crystal Cubism","post-impressionism"],"question":"The painting \"The Persistence of Memory\" by ‎Salvador Dalí is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"I Love Lucy","incorrectAnswers":["The Brady Bunch","Sanford and Son","My Favourite Martian"],"question":"What popular sitcom made its first appearance in 1951 & ran until 1957?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Switzerland","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Sweden","Norway"],"question":"What country used to sometimes be referred to by its Latin name of Helvetia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Beckett","Oscar Wilde","Jonathan Swift"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Spain & Portugal ","incorrectAnswers":["North Korea & South Korea","Malaysia & Singapore","Sweden & Norway"],"question":"Which 2 Countries Occupy The Iberian Peninsular?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Plastics.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Hello, gorgeous.\"","\"Fasten your seatbelts. It's going to be a bumpy night.\"","\"We’re goin’ streaking!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Graduate'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Very low temperatures","incorrectAnswers":["Lightning","Measurement","Victorian literature"],"question":"What is Cryology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Love is the fountain of life","incorrectAnswers":["Such is life","Through fire, nature is reborn whole","Virtue strives for what is difficult"],"question":"How does that Latin phrase 'Fons vitae caritas' translate into English?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Dravidian","incorrectAnswers":["Austronesian","Afroasiatic","Sino-Tibetan"],"question":"The language 'Malayalam' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beauty and the Beast","incorrectAnswers":["The Lion King","Aladdin","The Little Mermaid"],"question":"Which animated movie theme did Celine Dion and Peabo Bryson sing in 1992?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Washington","incorrectAnswers":["Alaska","Vermont","Texas"],"question":"Which US state is nicknamed the Evergreen State?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Robert Walpole","incorrectAnswers":["William Pitt the Elder","William Pitt the Younger","Thomas Paine"],"question":"Who was the first Prime Minister of Great Britain?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Beatles","incorrectAnswers":["Pink Floyd","The Clash","Deep Purple"],"question":"Which English rock band released the album 'Let It Be'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Gluteal","incorrectAnswers":["Abdominal","Bicep","Pectoral"],"question":"What is the name used for the group of muscles around the buttocks?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Triple Alliance","incorrectAnswers":["The Tenochca Empire","The Empire of the Sun","The Toltec Empire"],"question":"What was another name for the Aztec Empire?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","Japan","Chile"],"question":"Which country are the Galapagos Islands part of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["In Flames","HammerFall","Katatonia"],"question":"Which Swedish pop group released the song 'Thank You for the Music'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Percussion","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Stringed","Brass"],"question":"What type of instrument are the castanets?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Andorra","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Algeria","Belgium"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Spain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Horse","incorrectAnswers":["Moose","Bird","Bat"],"question":"Which animal would you associate with the Ralph Lauren logo?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1917","incorrectAnswers":["1914","1941","1945"],"question":"In which year did the United States enter World War I?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"His Dog","incorrectAnswers":["His Wife","His Mother","His Alter Ego"],"question":"Paul McCartney wrote The Song \"Martha My Dear\". Who did he know who was named Martha?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Chicago Blackhawks","incorrectAnswers":["Chicago Thunder","Chicago Steelers","Chicago Suns"],"question":"Which of these is a hockey team based in Chicago?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Africa","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Central America","Europe"],"question":"Where in the world are artichokes originally from?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the album 'Strange Days'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Constantinople","incorrectAnswers":["Jerusalem","Istanbul","New Byzantium"],"question":"To What Was Byzantium Renamed In 330 AD?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"8 Maids A Milking","incorrectAnswers":["8 Lords a Leaping","8 Swans a Swimming","8 Jugglers Juggling"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the eighth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Secretes hormones and digestive enzymes","incorrectAnswers":["Controls body temperature","Filters blood","Produces oxygen"],"question":"What is the function of the pancreas?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Sommelier","incorrectAnswers":["Charnaud","Chimbaud","Caranee"],"question":"What is the term used for a trained wine professional?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Three equal horizontal bands of red blue and orange.","incorrectAnswers":["Three horizontal bands of yellow blue and red.","Red with a white cross that extends to the edges.","Two vertical bands of red with white square between them containing a red leaf."],"question":"What does the flag of Armenia look like?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"2003","incorrectAnswers":["1997","2000","2006"],"question":"Finding Nemo was released in which year?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madrid ","incorrectAnswers":["Lisbon","Paris","Rome"],"question":"Which European capital city stands on the Manzanares River?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Canada","incorrectAnswers":["France","Australia","Russia"],"question":"In which country was Greenpeace founded in 1971?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"International Date Line","incorrectAnswers":["The Equator","The Prime Meridian","The Blood Meridian"],"question":"Which imaginery line approximately follows the 180 degree meridian through the Pacific Ocean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Kraftwerk","incorrectAnswers":["Rammstein","Pink Floyd","The Stranglers"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled Trans-Europe Express","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malta","incorrectAnswers":["Croatia","Monaco","Liechtenstein"],"question":"Which of these countries borders Italy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jean-Paul Sartre","incorrectAnswers":["Baruch Spinoza","Socrates","Epicurus"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Everything that exists is born for no reason, carries on living through weakness, and dies by accident'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"David Petraeus","incorrectAnswers":["Stanley McChrystal","James Mattis","John Allen"],"question":"Who was the U.S. general in charge in Afghanistan?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Speed","incorrectAnswers":["The Matrix","John Wick","Bill & Ted's Bogus Journey"],"question":"Which Keanu Reeves movie sequel has the subtitle '2: Cruise Control'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York Red Bulls","incorrectAnswers":["New York Sounders","New York Whitesox","New York Royals"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in New York?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Battle of the Bulge","incorrectAnswers":["Invasion of Normandy","Battle of Stalingrad","Pearl Harbor"],"question":"What is the name of the 1944 German counteroffensive that was beaten back by allied units?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"CPU","incorrectAnswers":["Motherboard","RAM","Hard Drive"],"question":"Which Part Of A Computer Is Responsible For Carrying Out Instructions?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Colin Firth","incorrectAnswers":["Sean Penn","Billy Bob Thornton","Jean-Claude Van Damme"],"question":"Which actor has starred in both The King's Speech and The English Patient?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Breathing","incorrectAnswers":["Pushing","Emotions","Noise"],"question":"What does psychoprophylaxis teach a mother to control and relax during pregnancy and childbirth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Falkland Islands","incorrectAnswers":["Gold","Nuclear Weapons","Industrial Sabotage"],"question":"What was the war between Argentina and Great Britan over?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Destiny's Child","incorrectAnswers":["TLC","All Saints","Spice Girls"],"question":"Which band did Beyoncé start her career with?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Garfish","incorrectAnswers":["Axolotl","Gladiator Beetle","Albatross"],"question":"The __________ has green bones.","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Lingerie","incorrectAnswers":["Corsetry","Foundation garments","Intimates"],"question":"What is the fancy name for women's underwear, which is derived from a French word?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Moscow","incorrectAnswers":["Zürich","Barcelona","Rotterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Russia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Baseball","incorrectAnswers":["Football","Soccer","Basketball"],"question":"What is the name of the sport covered in the book \"Pinstripe Empire\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Iceni","incorrectAnswers":["Gangani","Cassi","Brigantes"],"question":"Of What Tribe Was Boadicea The Head?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bob the Builder","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas the Tank Engine","Spongebob Squarepants","Scooby-Doo"],"question":"Which children's TV character has friends called Muck, Lofty, and Scoop?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1963","incorrectAnswers":["1957","1969","1975"],"question":"In which year was The Great Escape released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Red","Black","White"],"question":"In The Matrix, which pill would have returned Neo to the fabricated reality of the Matrix with no memory of what happened?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Arachne","incorrectAnswers":["Spidos","Tarantula","Creepius"],"question":"In Greek mythology who did Athena turn into a spider?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind","incorrectAnswers":["The Usual Suspects","Beauty and the Beast","Pulp Fiction"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A couple undergoes a medical procedure to have each other erased from their memories.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Winklepicker","incorrectAnswers":["Tittynope","Dipthong","Finifugal"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'style of shoe or boot in the 1950s with a sharp and long pointed toe'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Angel Falls","incorrectAnswers":["Niagara Falls","Victoria Falls","Olympus Falls"],"question":"What is the world's highest waterfall?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bat ","incorrectAnswers":["Dog","Cat","Horse"],"question":"Which animal appears on the Bacardi Logo?","difficulty":"medium"},